<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natasha Wu</title>
    <description>A designer who codes and writes about life
</description>
    <link>http://natashawu.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://natashawu.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 10:59:33 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 10:59:33 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Future Self (01/??)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Future Natasha,&lt;br /&gt;
These are some of your current thoughts at 25 (in no particular order).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a second to chill every now and again (You have way too much white hair for a 25-year-old. Just sayin’).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be present. You never know when the best moment of your life is going to end. Don’t take it for granted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Believe in yourself, or else no one else will.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are braver than you think. Remember to have confidence in yourself and your abilities. They will surprise you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, remember that these are things you love in life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your family &amp;amp; your friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being creative - whether it’s through design, development, painting, writing, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Awesome food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dancing &amp;amp; being healthy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of this letter, you were having trouble with figuring out what you wanted to do with your life. Typical quarter-life crisis stuff. As of now, here’s your list of completely “blue sky” dreams (aka dreams without a filter of reality placed over them):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run my own design studio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work at a famous bakery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Own a bakery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Become an awesome designer with coding skills to match&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work abroad while traveling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dance in a dance company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make money doing what I love / love my job&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make &amp;amp; save enough money that I can take care of myself and my parents without having to worry about unforeseen events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be one of those people who can sketch cool things on busses / trains&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start an organization that teaches life skills to high-school students&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save a life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to really sew and make something I can wear&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start a vegetable garden&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Become an expert at something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perform on stage with someone famous and/or be interviewed by someone famous&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participate in a competitive cooking show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that by the time you read this again, you’ll have accomplished some or maybe even all of these dreams in some way, shape, or form. You deserve the best. And if you aren’t getting it now, you should change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With love,&lt;br /&gt;
Past Natasha&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2016/07/19/dear-future-self-01.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2016/07/19/dear-future-self-01.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life in SF Thus Far</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wish I had written more blog posts between this last one this next one. It’s been a little over a year and a month since I started this blog and here’s what I’ve been up to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late-September, 2015 - Moving back to California&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first made the decision to move back home, it felt like I was admitting defeat. While I had received multiple job offers from companies in Chicago, I didn’t feel like any of them were the right opportunity for me. I felt like I was so close to “making it” in a new city. I had a new set of skills under my belt, I had a whole new network of friends, but I just couldn’t seem to find that perfect job offer. Unfortunately, I was slowly, but surely draining my bank account. So I spent my birthday weekend in Chicago, said goodbye to friends, new and old, and reluctantly flew home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November, 2015 - What I learned from TAing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months later, still without a full-time job, I accepted a teaching assistant position from the coding boot camp that I’d graduated from – they were opening up a branch in San Francisco. I remember wishing that I could have been one of those role model TAs, working at a fancy new job post-graduation. I wanted to be able to tell people that I’d done it, I’d become a software engineer, not a teaching assistant. But I accepted the position regardless because I needed the work experience, and the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class started and something horrible happened – when asked to explain something, I realized how unfamiliar I was with some of the topics I had just learned six months ago. The first couple days I experienced major impostor syndrome. It was like walking on stage to perform a something you’d practiced for months only to realize you’d forgotten most of a piece. It sucked. (I can’t believe I’m publicly admitting this but…) There were times when I purposely avoided eye contact with students because I was afraid that I wouldn’t be able to answer their questions. I felt so pressured to know everything about programming. But I didn’t know everything, in fact it was quite the opposite. I knew VERY little about programming and to this day, I still feel that I have so much to learn. I think that’s what they don’t tell you after these coding bootcamps. They don’t tell you that what you’ve learned is a very basic foundation for something much bigger, something that never ends. Programming is a field designed for people who truly never want to stop learning. And that makes the field so wonderful, yet so daunting at the same time. If you love to solve problems, you will never get bored. But you will also never know everything – you will never know all the languages, all the rules, or all the gotchas. Hopefully, with experience, what you will learn is how to solve problems like an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three most important things I learned from TAing (aside from just relearning things that I had forgotten):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to debug the weirdest problems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to explain complicated concepts using everyday English&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to be okay with not having all the answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know it then, but this position would turn out to be crucial to me getting my next job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January, 2016 - My First Software Engineering Position!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked into a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February, 2016 - Why did you do it, Nick Fuelling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Fuelling lived in a room in Noe Valley. He showed me the room I would be renting from him and it was perfect. We met up a few days later at a 24-hour donut shop up the street to sign the lease. The week I’d be moving in, I found out that Nick Fuelling scammed me and 30 other people out of our deposit money. He walked away with 70 grand in cashed checks and Venmo payments. I lost some of my faith in humanity that day, but also like to think that I grew a lot from that experience. And maybe next time, my skepticism will kick in sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March, 2016 - The Bed Frame Fiasco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having large packages delivered to your door when you live in the middle of a busy street and on a steep incline is just not a good idea. Parts of your package will get lost. You will spend hours on the phone with customer service people. And while some of them will be extremely helpful, it will eventually become apparent that you should have just spent the extra money renting a car to pick up your furniture yourself or paying a little bit more for furniture that will be delivered and assembled for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May, 2016 - All Good Things…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2016/05/27/life-in-sf-thus-far.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2016/05/27/life-in-sf-thus-far.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Post-Graduation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What most people don’t tell you about graduating from any sort of educational institution – whether it’s a 4-year univerity or a coding boot camp – is that the hard work is just beginning. Getting a job is one of the toughest jobs out there.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/10/09/post-graduation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/10/09/post-graduation.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #106 - The End Marks The Beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here marks the end of the boot camp and the beginning of my life as a developer. I can’t be more excited to continue to learn more about programming and grow into a stronger developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to continue posting my thoughts here, so if you’re interested in seeing where this path leads me…stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/08/09/day-onehundredsix.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/08/09/day-onehundredsix.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #103 - Judgement Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s the day! And here’s what I’ve got: 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devourgoodfood.com&quot; title=&quot;:Devour&quot;&gt;devourgoodfood.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/showcase1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/showcase2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for coming out to visit, friends :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/visitors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I have friends!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congrats, Emperor Penguins! We did it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/emperor_penguins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ACLTC: Emperor Penguins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/08/06/day-onehundredthree.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/08/06/day-onehundredthree.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #100 - Remembering to Give Thanks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Day after day of this adventure here in Chicago, I am reminded of how I wouldn’t be here without the support of my friends and family. Thank you to everyone who believed in me :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nothing beats family&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kiks.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging out w. Kiks!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lily.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lily&#39;s first visit to Chicago&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kevin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Best boyfriend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/besties.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Besties!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/harker_reunion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mini high school reunion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/jonny.png&quot; alt=&quot;Skype date w. Jonny!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/isaac2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Skype date w. Isaac!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/world.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On top of the world&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rachael.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We&#39;re on a boat!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra special thanks to this guy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/eric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Best everything&quot; /&gt;
I can’t thank you enough for your patience, time and kindness. If there were a “Best Personal TA” award, you’d get it for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/08/03/day-onehundred.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/08/03/day-onehundred.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #74 - Prying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been working on our capstones for a good couple weeks now and it’s been a lot of hard work, but pretty rewarding as well. For me, one of the most frustrating parts about creating my Rails app has been debugging. Throughout the course, we’ve learned how to use IRB and Rails console as tools for debugging. But to be honest, Rails console still freaks me out – the syntax is really difficult for me to remember and one misplaced curly brace immediately returns a whole slew of error messages. User friendliness rating on a scale of 1 to 10: -3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was asking one of our TAs, Trevor, for help on my project today and he showed me this great alternative to IRB and Rails console called Pry. Pry-rails is a gem that allows you to run, pause and inspect code that you’re running on your local machine. It’s almost like a time-turner for code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part: 2-step installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, add the following gem to your gem file: 
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem &#39;pry-rails&#39;, :group =&amp;gt; :development&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to use it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put the words &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;binding pry&lt;/code&gt; wherever you think your code may be triggering an error.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rails server&lt;/code&gt; in Terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll see that the loader for the web page will start to move slower. Go into Terminal and you’ll see that it now shows something along the lines of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[1] pry(#&amp;lt;nameofinspectedfile&amp;gt;)&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type anything that you would normally be able to type into Rails console into Pry to try and figure out why your code is breaking!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’re ready to “un-pause” the code, type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/code&gt; and the code should run through to the end again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/07/08/day-seventyfour.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/07/08/day-seventyfour.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #57 - Ready, Set, Go!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re already at Week 7 and that means (cue fanfare…or ominous dun-dun-DUUUN) it’s time to start on our capstones! Stay tuned to find out what I’m building :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/06/21/day-fiftyseven.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/06/21/day-fiftyseven.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #31 - Intro to Rails</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior to this course, I was telling anyone who asked that I would be learning Ruby on Rails, not knowing at all what Ruby or Rails really was. A typical conversation went like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, cool! Do you know what languages you’ll be learning at the bootcamp?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, we’ll be starting off with Ruby and going on to Ruby on Rails.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nice!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;both smiling, nodding and equally confused&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, today changed all that. Historically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rails was created as an open source project in 2004 by, co-founder of Basecamp and supposed programming badass, David Heinemeier Hansson (from this point forward referred to as DHH). I don’t know much about DHH, but he’s pretty famous in the coding world. And according to his Wikipedia page, he also drives race cars! I’d say that’s pretty badass.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rails is basically a giant Ruby gem (but most people call it a framework) where a lot of people wrote a lot of code to make it easier to get a website up and running quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails follows a model called MVC, which stands for “model-view-controller.” This is the convention that Rails uses to organize where code goes in a web application.* In very simplified terms, a controller tells a model what to do. A model grabs the appropriate data from the database (based on what the controller tells it to get) and passes it to the view. A view generates an output for the user to see based on the data that the model passes to it. Of course, there’s a little more back and forth and it’s not always a perfect loop, but that’s how I like to think of it in a general sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our class, we like to think of the flow as being RCV – “routes-controller-view.” In the routes file, you list all the possible web request combinations for your site. That means that if you want to have: thingsilove.com/cookies/index, thingsilove.com/cookies/about and thingsilove.com/cookies/new, you would have to list this in the routes file in the following fashion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;get “/index” =&amp;gt; &#39;cookies#index’&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; is the verb, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/index&lt;/code&gt; is the url, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cookies&lt;/code&gt; is the controller and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the controller action. Remember, a &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/05/25/day-thirty.html&quot;&gt;web request&lt;/a&gt; is an HTTP verb + a URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, all these rules and conventions seemed kind of daunting, but I quickly realized how much of a pain it would be to make a website without them. Everything would be a mess of a billion files – with random names, in random folders. In that situation, I don’t even want to think about trying to pick up something another developer has already started. So thank you, Rails (and I guess DHH + co.) for making life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait, “web application?” Don’t you mean “web site?” Or “mobile application?” No, I mean “web application.” And yes, it is confusing. I like to think that most modern websites are web applications – they require user interaction to be useful. Web applications allow users to do anything from comment on a post to look up a destination on an interactive map. Web sites, on the other hand, are static pieces of the Internet that display information for the user to consume – think of your local bar or grocery store’s online website. You can’t comment on anything or shop online, the only thing you can do is read about today’s specials and find out what their store hours are. For further explanation, look &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visionmobile.com/blog/2013/07/web-sites-vs-web-apps-what-the-experts-think/&quot; title=&quot;Web sites vs. Web Apps&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/05/26/day-thirtyone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/05/26/day-thirtyone.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day #30 - What&#39;s in a Web Request?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You go to the address bar in the browser, type in “facebook.com” and viola!, you see the familiar blue and white website frequented by millennials (ok, it’s really cross-generational now – my two-year-old cousin and my seventy-eight-year-old grandma both have a Facebook) around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what really happens when you type in that web address?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think back, to the days of typing “http://” as a prefix. Yeah, I know, it’s been a while. But that is the beginning of a web request, or an HTTP request. HTTP is the simple protocol (kind of like a language) that browsers and servers use to communicate with each other. Basically, when you type in that address, your computer sends a web request to get something (a file, an image, etc.) from a server. The server then passes its response to the browser where you (hopefully) see what you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the best of my current knowledge, web request always contains an HTTP verb and a URL. An HTTP verb defines the action to be taken on the URL and the URL tells the server where to look for the appropriate information that it will eventually send back to the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, my friends, is what I learned about web requests today in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://natashawu.github.io/2015/05/25/day-thirty.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://natashawu.github.io/2015/05/25/day-thirty.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
